Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

Android Developer

@ hadi.pro.dev@gmail.com

+34 645 86 91 03

Barcelona, Spain

github.com/hadilq

M medium.com/@hadilq.dev

in linkedin.com/in/hadilg

Summary

A curious developer with over 15 years of experience in software development, where almost 5 years of his experience covers Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student. An introvert person who has profound learning and contributing skills. A creative, value driven and passionate developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, testable and efficient apps to make the world a better place to live.

A person whose goal is to surround himself with happy, creative, motivative and clever persons, so his talent becomes flourished.

He's interested in Data Science, Machine Learning, Functional Programming, Differentiable Programming, Category Theory, Math, etc. so constantly looking forward to learning related technologies to use in Mobile apps

Experience

Senior Android Developer

at Letgo

d Oct. 2019 - Present

Parcelona, Spain

Letgo is the biggest classified marketplace in Turkey with 15+ million apps installed on Android de-

Mission:

- After his first week of start, he could convince the professional Letgo team to allow him to jump right into the migrations of Kotlin, RxJava and Dagger.
- Fix a couple of bugs and implement multiple features and their A/B Testing
- · Known as "The man who broke the escape room" to emphasize his ability to think out of the box **Technologies**:

- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Room, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD
- · Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco, Ktlint, Fastlane
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Figma
- · New Relic, Firebase, Amplitude, Leanplum, etc.

Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

🛗 Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor is one of two lead classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million overall users and 344+ million sessions.

Missions:

- Increase the number of users per day from 0.5+ million to 1.5+ million in a year.
- · As functional manager of the Android team, he was responsible for the code quality of the Sheypoor app. He coached the team to practice design patterns, clean code, and using app architecture, along with updating libraries and adding new features with focus on agility and UX
- Implementing new design of the entire app, including rebranding for summer campaign
- Improving the legacy code quality by adding Dagger and Kotlin.

Technologies

- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Butter Knife, Greendao, etc.
- · Agile, Kanban, Git Flow, CI/CD
- · Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco
- Pivotal Tracker, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Zeplin, etc.

Senior Android Developer

at Myket

m Sep. 2015 - Des. 2017

Tehran, Iran

Myket is one of two lead app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users.

- Starting TDD and installing Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.
- · Implementing features such as handling deeplinks, search page, inbox page, etc.

Technologies

- Dagger 2, Volley, OneSignal, EventBus, OrmLite, etc.
- · Agile, Scrum, Git Flow
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Gitlab, Jfrog, Jenkins

Java and C# developer

at Soha System

mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

Tehran, Iran

SOHA is formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards.

Missions: • Implementing RFID card reader Android app via bluetooth connection. Implementing Android and desktop apps.

Lecturer at Universities

Mashhad, Iran

After two years of enrollment by conscription, he had been starting his work in two universities Payame Noor University and Sadjad University of Technology

· Application of Computers in Physics, Mathematical Physics, etc.

Article / Repository

🗘 2020 Library: A Kotlin compiler plugin that generates trackable method

M 2020 Medium post: Save State By Using RxJava or Kotlin Flow M 2020 Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM

2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and upstreams in RxJava

🔾 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and Kotlin Coroutines

2019 Sample App: Movie Challenge

2018 Log4k Library: Easy logging library, but unfortunately it's in Sheypoor repository

☑ 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Reactive MVVM architectural pattern O 2018 Sample App: Clean Architecture

M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Loading entities from database and server API by using RxJava M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: LiveData with single events

2018 LiveEvent library: It's useful to propagate single event to View

Education

Sharif University Of Technology Payame Noor University

B.Sc

M.Sc in Physics in Physics

O Tehran, Iran Mashhad, Iran

Tools / Skills

Android

Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging/ViewModel Multidex/Test/Data Binding/WorkManager/Room Android Architecture Components/JetPack Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/. Kotlin Multiplatform/Kotlin Coroutines
Kotlin Compiler Plugin/... View Binding/Butter Knife/ObjectBox/...

Architecture

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture MVVM/MVP/RMVVM

Principle

Clean Code/SOLID **Object Oriented Programming Functional Programming** Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle

Design Pattern

Factory/Builder/Singleton/... Adapter/Facade/Proxy/Visitor/. Strategy/Chain of responsibility/...

Android test library

JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/Jacoco/...

Build Tool

Gradle/Sbt/Maven/Ant/Make/...

Command Line Tool

grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/... adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/...

Development Tool

Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/Travis/CircleCi/...

Programing Language

Java/Kotlin/Scala/Haskell/Python Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Rust/..

Operating System

Linux(Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

Special Honor

- 2019 Had an offer from Kik, Kitechener, Canada
- 2019 Had an offer from Letgo, Barcelona, Spain 2019 Had an offer from CRITICAL Techworks, BMW,
- Porto, Portugal

 2019 Had an offer from The Next Big Thing, Berlin, Germany
 - · 2018 Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor
- 2007 Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam

Language

English: Advance Farsi: Native

Built at May 17, 2020